<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Nicolei Ocana's Blog</title>
        <link>https://nicoleiocana.github.io/blog/</link>
        <description>2020 Outreachy Internship Blog</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>nicoleiocana@gmail.com (Nicolei Ocana)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>nicoleiocana@gmail.com (Nicolei Ocana)</webMaster>
        <copyright>Copyright (c)2020</copyright>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 June 2020 14:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <image>
            <title>Nicolei Ocana's Blog</title>
            <link>https://nicoleiocana.github.io/blog/</link>
            <url>https://nicoleiocana.github.io/img/fenix-144.png</url>
            <width>144</width>
            <height>144</height>
        </image>
        <item>
            <title>Who I Am</title>
            <link>https://nicoleiocana.github.io/blog/#7</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nicoleiocana.github.io/blog/#7</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>
                        I'm Nicolei Ocana. The core values that best reflect my identity are
                        community, responsibility, and meaningful work. I poke fun of my 
                        38 years of age; all jest aside, my experiences contributed
                        to how I personify these core values.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        The characteristic of community is important because all individuals
                        deserve an equal chance. There are matters that are out of one's
                        control negatively affecting their education, their right to stand
                        up for what they believe in, and informing themselves of what is going
                        on outside of where they live. If I had a chance to bring the
                        community together by offering a resolution to these issues, I would.
                        I cannot be a passive participant while there exists some who are less
                        fortnuate than I am only because they were born in an oppressive environment. 
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        As a representative of the older generation, I feel it is important
                        to exhibit charity to help those who are in the same position as I
                        once was: confused and overwhelmed. Web development can be
                        outrageously difficult without the proper guidance. Responsibility is
                        exemplified whenever I have the opportunity to help anyone with a 
                        "noob" question. No one should have to feel threatened when they are
                        simply looking for direction when developing their technological passion.
                        I'm glad to patiently offer my support when someone is stuck; I remember
                        being at that point once and it is my responsibility to offer the same
                        mentorship that I once received.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        A job well done is its own reward. Demonstrating meaningful work is projected
                        from volunteering my time, knowing that financial compensation
                        truly isn't the movitating factor to complete any task to the best of my
                        abilities. Any responsibility is met with the same enthusiasm and diligence.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        My motivation to apply to Outreachy is to serve as an example that 
                        no matter your age, your educational background, or hardships you face in life,
                        anyone has a chance to achieve their goals. All the hard work, sacrifice, and
                        perseverance will result in accomplishment. Believe in yourself and
                        never give up.
                    </p>
                ]]>
            </description>
            <author>nicoleiocana@gmail.com (Nicolei Ocana)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Null Set</title>
            <link>https://nicoleiocana.github.io/blog/#8</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nicoleiocana.github.io/blog/#8</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 June 2020 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>
                        You don't know what you don't know. When it comes to finding solutions in
                        software engineering, the analogy is this: not only do you need to find
                        a needle in a haystack, but you do not know which haystack to begin searching
                        in a multitude of haystacks. And there are similar looking needles that are
                        not the exact needle you are looking for. And sometimes the needle may have
                        have been in one location but since relocated. I wish I were joking.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Struggling is inevitable, inescapable. The key to success is to approach the situation in a positive light.
                        Embrace the challenge. To exercise your capability in the face of a worthy opponent should
                        be viewed as a wonderful opportunity to be rewarded with triumph when you overcome
                        the adversity. Identify the calming peace that a solution exists so your
                        effort is not futile. Remember, the answer is out there, you just have to find it. Nothing
                        separates you from an esteemed software engineer other than the fact that they have
                        polished their insight regarding how to discover the resolution.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Understand that an experienced software engineer (SWE) does not live in constant turmoil of
                        struggling nor is immune to getting stuck on an issue. No, s/he has developed and nurtured
                        the balanced habit of effectively and efficiently progressing through a problem when faced with
                        one. This habit includes pursuing a solution in a reasonable amount of time to focus on a problem
                        versus giving up too quickly. An experienced SWE has amassed the crucial, trusted documentation to
                        research and its respective places on the Internet. A seasoned engineer identifies when he or she
                        is experiencing burn out and distances themselves from the problem for the day, ready to return to the issue
                        reenergized after a good night's rest (afternoon nap?). And finally,
                        realizing that the scope of the problem is better handled by your superior: maybe the
                        biggest element surrounding getting stuck had more to do with your pride rather than
                        your intelligence? 
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Identify who you are as a software engineer and strive to behave that way
                        every day. Are you comfortable accepting that you do not know all aspects of the
                        project you are working on? Are you willing to be disciplined and commit to hours
                        of researching when you need to inform yourself of supplementary knowledge
                        surrounding your specific issue? Are you patient with yourself when you feel like
                        giving up? Do you have the awareness to ask for help when you realize that you have
                        tried your best? Most experienced software engineers demonstrate the mastery of
                        their emotional quotient as opposed to their I.Q. Once you find closure that we
                        all possess an empty set of optimal tactics to utilize regarding struggling at the beginning of our career,
                        it is easier to begin filling our empty set of behavioral tools with habits to thrive in our field.
                    </p>
                ]]>
            </description>
            <author>nicoleiocana@gmail.com (Nicolei Ocana)</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>